Guide to the Arthur Ovaska papers 1888-2000
Arthur Ovaska papers.
- Series V. Work and miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous drawing, Date Unknown; 26
    1 original drawing, ink on vellum. Depicts section drawing of a tower with sloping sides and interior staircase. Dotted lines shown bouncing off sides of tower, relating to a set of squares labeled with numbers (structure, wind, light ?). Drawing of a boat (?) in lower right corner. No dates, labels, titles, or other identifying information
  - Architectural Analysis Student Work, Date Unknown; 26
    Work by students from A.Ovaska's course - Architectural Analysis 231. Original drawings, ink on vellum. Depicts various analysis drawings of important architectural works, primarily facades and plans - S. Vito DâAntivole Cimtero Brion 1970, Carlo Scarpa, An Architectural Analysis, by Lyn Lopez, Arch. Anal. 231, complete drawing set, original drawings, ink on vellum
    Project 1: Notre Dame de Chartres, Chartres, France, 13th Century, by John Chen and Lilis Wu, complete drawing set, original drawings, ink on vellum
    Project 2: Frank Lloyd Wright, Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, NY NY 1965 complete drawing set, original drawings, ink on vellum
  - Auditorium Drawings, Date Unknown; 27
    Original drawings, ink on vellum. Plans and sections depicting a proposal for an auditorium
  - Miscellaneous drawings, Date Unknown; 27
    Drawing set, original ink on vellum. Plans and section
    Design for a school building (?), plans depicting lecture hall, classrooms
  - Lee Hodgeden, Design: Museum at Aalborg - Originals, Sandra Schwart, Date Unknown; 27
    Original drawing set, ink on vellum. Plans and sections for the design of a museum - No year, titles, etc.
  - Aalto Paimio, Date Unknown; 28
    Plan, section, and shadow plan drawings of Aaltoâs Paimio. Original drawings, ink on vellum. Likely student work completed for an architectural analysis course (?). No names, titles, labels, or other identifying information
  - Grand Central, Date Unknown; 28
    Complete drawing set analyzing Grand Central Terminal in NYC: Plan, section, elevation, axonometric drawings of GCT and the surrounding urban context. Original drawings, ink on vellum. Likely student work completed for an architectural analysis course (?). No name, label, date, or other identifying information
  - Van der Poll, Aalto DWGs Hedemora, Date Unknown; 29
    Drawing set of Aalto's Hedemora. Original drawings, ink on vellum. 2 plans, 1 section. Likely student work completed for an architectural analysis course (?). No name, label, date, or other identifying information
  - Student Work: Maison Cook, Eric Boulet, Date Unknown; 30
    Set of plan and sections drawings, pencil on paper, labeled Eric Boulet, Section 3
    Set of plan, section, elevation, axonometric (final?) drawings, ink on vellum
    Likely a small housing project
  - Facades on Film, Date Unknown; 30
    Set of drawings transferred to black, flmy paper, Depicting drawings of front facade studies of major classical architecture
  - Miscellaneous, Date Unknown; 30
    Set of miscellaneous items from A.Ovaska's archive that were not contained within rolls, tubes, folders. Plan of city blocks, numbered lots, London (?), 11x17 photocopy
    Colored map labeled, Karte von Berlin, Bezirk, Schoeberg colored print on glossy paper
    Plan sketch of area within a train station (pencil on paper)
    Exhibition poster labeled “Nekropolis: Europäïsche Totenstädte, ihre Anlage undo Architektur ihre Bewohner, Michael Ruetz 100 Photographien 1968-1976”
    Plan drawing, completely misc, photocopy, labeled Fourth Floor
    Napkin sketch labeled Teisch 519 State
    Elevations for a project in Ithaca, showing elevations from Stewart Ave, Williams St., Cascadilla Gorge, Highland Place - possibly Ithaca City Hall project?
    Trace paper sketch of plan, completely misc
  - Photocopies, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Photocopied 11x17 packet, depicting plans of ancient temples, old cathedrals, theater, and ancient architecture
  - Photocopies, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    Photocopies, organized into 6 sections, of historic garden precedents, depicting plan drawings, sections, photographs SMALL
  - Olin Lib./AAP Design proposal, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Working drawings for feasibility study of Olin Library / AAP. Original drawings, freehand ink on paper / trace paper.
    Photocopies of drawings / precedents
  - Feasibility Study Expansion of Olin Library /AAP, 1988 (Box 1)
    Complete design packet / analysis for the expansion of AAP. Presents 4 schemes - A, B, C D, - plans, sections, elevations, axonometric, photographs of model
  - Boston, Date Unknown (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Stacks of photocopies of various sizes (primarily 11x17) of sections/fragments of line drawings appears to be plans, site plans
    1-2 original hand sketches, ink on card stock, trace paper
  - Maps of Berlin, site study, Date Unknown (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Set of analysis maps of Berlin in color - traffc patterns, zoning, etc.
    Misc packet labeled Anatomy of Forms - What the Forms Are (Single Forms - Form Elements) â depicting iterations of square/rectangular form manipulations
    Folder containing misc items labeled Housing Types / NYC Grid - containing newspaper article, reading packet, photocopies
    Folder containing misc items labeled Milton Keynes - containing packet depicting housing typologies in Berlin/ other cities, mixed drawings/writing
    Misc. collection of drawings seeming to sample 1-2 drawings from each of A. Ovaska's projects - Welfare Island, Watkins Glen, Braunschweig (all prints, no originals) SMALL
  - Miscellaneous, Date Unknown (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Misc. collection of trace paper sketches - no labels, dates, or other identifying information.
    1 drawing, possibly sections through roods, labeled Offener Bauwettbewerb / Wohnbauung Mit Kindertagesstatte auf Dem Morbider Werder, Schnitte Stadtbahnviadukt M 1:200
  - Miscellaneous, Date Unknown; 1970-1981 (Mapcase-folder 9)
    Contains 3 different projects: Original complete drawing set from Design 106 - Ithaca City Hall, ink on vellum; Set of prints from Berlin Museum Garten, 1981, stamped by Kolhoff and Ovaska perspectives and plans; Misc. set of ink on vellum drawings, depicting iterations of city block planning; 2 original site plan drawings, ink/colored pencil on paper (Moscow?)
  - Sketch plans, Date Unknown (Mapcase-folder 13)
    Set of related sketches, all in plan, ink/colored pencil on trace paper. No label, date, title, or other identifying information. Site plans (?)
  - Miscellaneous, Date Unknown (Mapcase-folder 18)
    1 Board, depicting a longitudinal hand-drawn section / elevation. No labels, possibly relates to BMG project
- Series VI. Maps
  - Maps, Date Unknown (Mapcase-folder 18)
    Map of Berlin. Line drawing, original print (?). Labeled Berlin, Südliche Friedrichstadt, Der Senator für Bau-und Wohnungswesen V-1980
  - Maps of Berlin, Date Unknown; 11
    Prints on Vellum
  - Assorted maps, 1888; 12
    Rand McNally map of Contemporary United States (no date); 4 maps of Berlin 1888 (prints) labeled Situations plan von der Haupt-und ResidenzStadt Berlin und Umgegend beerbeitet von W. Leibenow
  - Assorted maps, 1935-1980; 14
    Multiple maps of Friedrichstadt; 1 Map labeled Bearbeiteit 1980; 1 Map labeled Stadtplan von Berlin 1935-1941
  - Maps of Berlin, 1985; 14
    4 Maps of Berlin, prints, scale 1:4000 (M); 5 Maps of Berlin, prints, labeled Herausgeber: Der Senator for Stadtentwicklung und Umweltschultz, Berlin 1985
  - Geological Survey South Shore, Date Unknown; 20
    Set of maps
    Geological survey of Massachusetts - Weymouth Quadrangle, Nantasket Beach, Cohasset Quadrangle
  - University of Maryland Map, Date Unknown; 31
  - Figure ground map labeled, Boston Proper, 1:400 1984, 1984; 31
  - Boston Chinatown, 1985; 31
    Figure ground map, labeled Central Boston, 1985
  - Assorted maps, Date Unknown; 31
    Figure ground map, labeled South End, print on vellum, depicting the South End of Boston
    Hand-drawn map fragment, ink on vellum
    Set of b/w print-outs of site maps, labeled Wassaic Developmental Center, Restructuring/Consolidation Study, Amenia, NY, Buckhurst Fish Hutton Katz
  - Maps of New Jersey, Date Unknown; 31
    Line drawing map of Hoboken, labeled City of Hoboken, New York, Mayo Lynch and Associates, revised 1972, revised 1976
    Figure ground map, also of Hoboken (?), no labels or text, print of original drawing on vellum
    Set of 3 Land Use maps of Hoboken, colored with red, yellow, and black, each color indicating information/classification
    Map of larger context labeled Map L900, Cornell University Libraries Maps, Micro texts, and Newspapers
  - Campus Plan, 1965; 31
    Map of Cornell University's campus, print on vellum, labeled Campus Plan: Cornell University, Ithaca NY, JNT November 1965
  - University of Virginia, Date Unknown; 31
    Figure ground map, print on paper, labeled University of Virginia Context Plan, Carr's Hill Precinct Study, Michael Dennis and Associates
    Set of 2 maps, 1 figure ground, 1 line drawing, depicting enlarged areas of the UVA Context Plan
    1 line drawing map, depicting UVA context plan (?), unlabeled, print on vellum
  - FG Jaipur, Date Unknown; 26
    Figure ground map of Jaipur, print on paper, with inverted figure ground map of the same image
  - Helsinki, Date Unknown; 26
    Line drawing of Helsinki, Finland, print on paper. 1:4000 metric scale.
  - University of Virginia, Date Unknown; 26
    Site / context maps of the University of Virginia
    Prints on vellum, of originally hand-drawn maps (?)
    2 maps printed as mirror images of correct reading
  - Chichen Itza, 1935; 27
    Set of maps labeled Map of the Ruins of Chichen Itza, Yucatan, Mexico, Carnegie Institution of Washington Publication, Surveyed in 1924/1932, Issued in 1935
  - Figure ground map of London, print on vellum, Date Unknown; 27
  - Athens, Date Unknown; 27
    Figure ground map of Athens, print in blue ink on paper. Line drawing map of the same image from the FG
  - Kimbolton/Writtle, Date Unknown; 28
    Set of maps depicting various areas within Chelmsford, England
    3 map fragments (not connected) of Kimbolton, prints on paper/vellum, varying scales
    Print of a hand-drawn site map, depicting roads leading out of site and their destinations
    Print of hand-drawn map, labeled Group 2: Unit 2
    Figure ground map, photocopy of print, depicting Writtle"
  - Greater London, Date Unknown; 28
    Set of 2 maps (1 duplicate) of Greater London
    Photocopies of maps from Cornell University Library - Maps, Micro texts, and Newspapers Cornell University Libraries
    1 map labeled Ordinance Survey, Scale 6 inches to 1 mile, Greater London depicting Camden LB, St. Marylebone BC, and the City of Westminster LB
    1 map labeled Ordinance Survey, Scale 6 inches to 1 mile, Greater London depicting Islington LB, Shoreditch and Finsbury BC, and London
  - New York City, Date Unknown; 28
    Axonometric map of NYC, Labeled New York, Map of Midtown Manhattan, Constantine Anderson 1961, The Manhattan Map Company Inc - Color print on glossy paper
  - Annapolis FG, Date Unknown; 28
    Figure ground map, print on paper, labeled City of Annapolis, Maryland
    Photocopy print of hand-drawn axonometric, likely depicting buildings in Annapolis
  - Greater London, Date Unknown; 28
    Map, vertical, labeled Ordinance Survey, Scale 6 inches to 1 mile, Greater London depicting Southwark LB, print on card stock paper
    Map, horizontal, Ordinance Survey, Scale 6 inches to 1 mile, Greater London depicting St. James Ward, Berkeley Ward, and Regent Street Ward
    Map, vertical, labeled Ordinance Survey, National Grid Plans, The Cities of London and Westminster Boro Const, Regent St Ward photocopy of print
  - Cornell Campus, Date Unknown; 29
    Line drawing map, print on vellum, of Cornell University's campus
  - Mayan Pelhal, Date Unknown; 29
    Roof plan map with shadows, labeled Pechal Campeche ". Print on paper
  - University of Virginia, Date Unknown; 29
    Map of UVA's campus, mirror image. Print on vellum. Labeled Carr's Hill Precinct Plan
  - Mayan Tikal, 1959; 29
    Map labeled The Ruins of Tikal, Department of Peten, Guatemala CA, University of Pennsylvania, Great Plaza 1959, Mapped in 1957-1959. Line drawing map, print on paper, show roof profiles.
  - Lugano, Date Unknown; 29
    Map labeled Lugano, Carta Nazionale della Svizzera 1:25000, Foglio 1353. Topographic / figure ground map, Color print
  - Venice Aerials, Date Unknown; 29
    Series of aerial photographs of Venice, all labeled Commune di Venezia, Assessorato All'Urbanistica, Siute sistema informativo urbano territorializzato, Scala 1:500
  - St. Die Etc. FG, Date Unknown; 29
    Set of graphic figure ground maps, prints on paper. Show positive / negative versions
  - Boston Maps, Date Unknown; 29
    Set of maps of Boston. Map of Boston mirrored image, labeled City of Boston, Topographic and Planimetric Survey, Boston Massachusetts 1962, depicts city blocks with numbered lots, print on paper
    Figure ground map, depicting a neighborhood in Boston, ink on vellum
    Map of Boston, labeled Zoning Districts - City of Boston Map 1 Boston Proper
  - Quintana Roo, Date Unknown; 30
    2 maps, photocopies of prints. 1 map labeled Peor es Nada Quintana Roo (a state within Mexico), depicting a site plan, each building labeled with a number
    1 map showing enlarged area of numbered buildings
  - Bath, Date Unknown; 30
    Map of Bath, England, labeled A New and Accurate Plan of the City of Path, to the present year, 1799, published by A. Taylor and W. Meyler - Photocopy of a print, from Cornell Libraries.
  - FG Munich Turin, Date Unknown; 30
    Figure ground map of an enlarged area of Munich, photocopy of print on paper
    2 figure ground maps of Turin, same image but inverted versions of each other
    Possibly a historic map of Turin, depicting Citadel (dating 1600s/1700s) on far left side of map
  - Cambridge, Date Unknown; 30
    Map of Boston, Cambridge area
  - Miscellaneous maps, Date Unknown; 30
    Set of 3 11x17 b/w photocopies of unlabeled maps. Depicts a city on the edge of a body of water
  - Ruins of Tikal, Date Unknown; 30
    Set of maps labeled Ruins of Tikal, Department of Peten, Guatemala CA, The Tikal Project, Edwin M Shook Director, University of Pennsylvania
    Line drawings depicting topography and the location of individual ruins.
    1 figure ground map